<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on Introspections in Bytes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on Introspections in Bytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2020-2024, Wai Jun Mak</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 15:30:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>65: Economics 10: A Commentary on Underdeveloped Economies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/post65/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 15:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/post65/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ugh this was a bit delayed (pardon the slight-out-of-orderness). This follows on from Post 64 (duh).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, I add to my thoughts on the economy from a macro perspective. From the broad trends and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.makwaijun.com/blog/post35/&#34;&gt;history&lt;/a&gt; of the global economy, to intangibility and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.makwaijun.com/blog/post43/&#34;&gt;rise of bullshit&lt;/a&gt; transition, and finally towards contextualising economic development models for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.makwaijun.com/blog/post64/&#34;&gt;developed economies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The world has undeniably been shaped by global powers and major economies - driving technology, competition and consumption trends.  An anecdote - I recall finding a Chinese restaraunt in the middle of a fringe city (Teresina) in Brazil; while similarly being able to find Peruvian grocies halfway across its country of origin Singapore. Its fascinating and indisputably beneficial - surely.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>64: Economics 9 - Economic Development For Developed Economies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/post64/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 15:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/post64/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;preamble&#34;&gt;Preamble&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am not economically trained and the thinking below could either come across as i) Bizarre, or ii) Obvious to those who read it. Welp, anyway:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is indisputable (come fight me bro) that a good economy - is one that keeps people employed well and in meaningful occupations thus creating social stability in a country.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the Post- WWII era, national economic development followed a strategem to bring themsleves out of poverty. It was reliant on developing countries integrating themselves into the global world order, building exportable skills, and carving out competitive niches to win.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>59: On Millenials and CryptoMania 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/post59/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 13:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/post59/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;cryptomaniallenials-and-the-loss-of-meaning&#34;&gt;Cryptomaniallenials and the loss of meaning&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Big question number two: How did this entirely new thing emerge?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Particularly so for a generation that had witnessed a global financial crisis - why is their risk tolerance so high?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Big question, here is my take: It is the perfect storm of several megatrends.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Financial:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An economy aflush with cash&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Economic:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An economy that values the intangible and non-physical products more than physical ones (link post)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A stripped out Millenial workforce facing high debt/expenses&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Weakened traditional wealth-growing prospects&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Social&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>58: On Millenials and CryptoMania 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/post58/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 13:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/post58/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ah Millenials. I mean &lt;em&gt;Millenials&lt;/em&gt; as I picture an old fellow spittling away with a brusque sneer: A pittance of morality; lazy, arrogant foolish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I keep seeing viewpoints how different generations perceive one another - with one baby boomer generation ruining the world into purgatory, and the second millenial generation squandering wealth and its perceived nurgatory (subsequent generations are too stuck in their phone games to matter in this debate&amp;hellip;until they&amp;rsquo;re able to infleunce votes).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>56: Commentary: Profiteering is in the Eye of the Beholder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/post56/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/post56/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a matter of building off previous posts, and to ensure the &amp;ldquo;permanance&amp;rdquo; of content amidst numerous evolving conceptual ideas, I&amp;rsquo;ll add some additional ideas / thoughts through separate posts. This way, if there are interesting articles I read along the way that are relevant to a past post, I&amp;rsquo;ll add a commentary such as this one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently (clearly not today, as I am hardly able to maintain a regular time to write), I came across an article by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/20/opinion/profits-competition-covid.html&#34;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt; by Peter Coy discussing how big boy pharma companies are making bank (well specifically, profits) off the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
