<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mak Wai Jun</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mak Wai Jun</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-UK</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 22:34:13 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The lifestack project</title>
      <link>/blog/post7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 22:34:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post7/</guid>
      <description>[Scope] Web Project 1: My &amp;ldquo;Lifestack&amp;rdquo; One of the projects I intended to host on this website was a visual representation of my intellectual (?) progress. This is in line with my first post, which spoke of the need to better understand my learning journey that has brought me here today.
It is meta-project that addresses its very conception.
Originating the Idea I studied sustainability, which got me interested into system dynamics and complexity science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Intolerance of Intolerance</title>
      <link>/blog/post6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 20:41:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post6/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topics to write in 2020</title>
      <link>/blog/post5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 21:25:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post5/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s post lays out some blog topics that I have been ruminating over for a while.
More subtly its another way to(hopefully) commit myself to a deadline before the end of the year.
Opening Thoughts I am glad that I have managed to have kept posting over the last few days. Gotta keep the momentum going.
I would imagine readership would be a good way of keeping motivated. Butttt thats better left for another time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Identity, Citizenship &amp; Belonging</title>
      <link>/blog/post4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 21:20:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post4/</guid>
      <description>In my last post, I had a notion about whether patriotism can exist in metropolises.
The obvious counterpoint is Hong Kong. A raw demonstration of fighting for one&amp;rsquo;s survival.
Were these for individual reasons? A manifestation of youth unrest? Those seeking to protect what is familiar and the current way of life? I am not sure.
In any case, it did set the scene for a contemplation about my own identity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the Hong Kong Crisis</title>
      <link>/blog/post3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 21:23:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post3/</guid>
      <description>Keeping Momentum Its been a while.
I should maintain a steady cadence to blogging.
But perhaps I should also let the process take its natural course.
Recent news triggered a short reaction. Specifically on&amp;hellip;.
Hong Kong The place renders an odd feeling in me.
I am, and fully identify as being Singaporean (perhaps an idea worth exploring in future posts) in citizenship, but I am half-Hong Konger in blood. I am also perhaps Hong Kong-er in name (canto surname, canto spelling) I have only been there twice in my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Template of my Own</title>
      <link>/blog/post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 16:25:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post2/</guid>
      <description>Update Another week - another revision.
Welcome to version two of site - rebuilt from scratch with a generoues does of customised appropriated snippets of code.
This guide in particular was helpful in laying out the groundwork from Hugo.
Still fairly minimalist, but I have much better control and understanding of where the various elements are situated.
Key take-aways from this session were:
 A slightly deeper understanding of the hugo framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>/projects/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 22:31:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/music/</guid>
      <description>After being coerced into music lessons for the better part of my childhood years - I was glad to have found something of a musical spark post-highschool. Unfettered from laborious exams and the pretentious contemporary pieces, I was keen on playing music that I wanted to.
Fairly basic and amateur-ish, but nonetheless a passion I enjoy and would love to have more time invested into.
Checkout my most viewed video!   Original Pieces   Gear Most videos were recorded with a Blue Yeti Microphone and Audacity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raison D&#39;etre</title>
      <link>/blog/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 18:31:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post1/</guid>
      <description>The blog is born If what I do is common - I tend to read the latest few posts and first post when visiting a new blog. So I hope dear reader, to make this count.
It took the better part of one and a half-ish days over the long weekend to get this up and running.
I had been mulling for a long time on having my own personal website.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>