<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Career on Introspections in Bytes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Career on Introspections in Bytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2020-2024, Wai Jun Mak</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 15:30:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>63: Career 3 - On Career</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/post63/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 15:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/post63/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a predominantly personal post - naive perhaps in the public domain, but nonetheless important guiding points for future endeavours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having said the waffly part, this post will aim to be a bit more grounded, to draw down the dreams into the realm of reality and practicality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Similarly, I shall phrase some of these as Tenets, and guiding principles that seeeeeems to have served me well within the confines of limited career thus far. To be snappy and not overanalysing, I&amp;rsquo;ll write this as a list of useful pointers, rather than a continuous segment of words. Where I&amp;rsquo;m able to, I find that some of these networks are linked to one antoher, in a self reinforcing virtuous system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>62: Career 2 - On Purpose</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/post62/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 15:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/post62/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;preamble-background-homework---individual-beliefs-and-values&#34;&gt;Preamble: Background homework - Individual beliefs and values&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a massive, hugeee prerequsite to thinking about how we feel about work must be developing an understanding and appreciation of our own worldviews.  (instrospective mUcH?). It starts with aligning our definition of purpose with the actions we take (like work) must sense of life&amp;rsquo;s ideology and what we deem to be more meaningful than others. Perhaps the thinking here may be thought-provoking - but never prescriptive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>61: Career 1 - On a Purposeful Career and Meaningful work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/post61/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 15:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/post61/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;preamble&#34;&gt;Preamble&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First of all, I am in a blessed position where I do not have to obsess about finances (the most relevant goal of work). Instead, I explore the more indulgent aspects of work, assuming we are able to put enough food on the table and live well. This is made possible with limited liabilities and a stable background, which I must remind myself not to take for granted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This series pens down my personal thinking behind work and its meaning - to act as an mental anchor to be deliberate, wise and free to make sound choices in this impactful area of life. It is as much a doctrine for career planning; as much as it is a balm for my soul, easily lost in a sea of choices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
